idropnews.com 2018-12-21

# Privacy Policy for iDrop News

iDrop News appreciates our readers and values your privacy. This Privacy Policy explains the information we collect, store, and use about you. iDrop News operates a website (the “ **Website** ”) and delivers a newsletter (the “ **Newsletter** ”).  By accessing and using our Website, you explicitly accept, without limitation or qualification, the collection, use, and transfer of the personal information and non-personal information (defined below) in the manner described in this Privacy Policy.  Please read this Policy carefully, as it affects your rights and liabilities under the law.  If you disagree with the way we collect and process personal and non-personal information, please do not use this Website.

## 1\. Types of Information We Collect.

We collect the following types of information about you.

1.1.  “Personal information” is information that can be used to identify a specific person.  For us, personal information means your name and/or e-mail address.

1.2.  “Non-personal information” is information that cannot be used to identify a specific person. It includes usage information about the Website such as: How much time do users spend on our site, where did they come from, and where do they go once they leave? It includes demographic information about visitors to the website, such as information on age or income or interests. It also includes information logged by our webserver, such as your IP address. It also includes information about how often users read the Newsletter.

##  **2\. How We Collect Information.**

2.1.  E-mail addresses are collected when you subscribe to our newsletter. We also receive e-mail addresses from Stack Commerce when you purchase from our store, and we receive names and e-mail addresses when you enter our random drawings.

2.2.  You may voluntarily give information to us, such as your demographic information or any comments that you leave under stories.

2.3.  We may use cookies to track usage information about the Website and the Newsletter. “Cookies” are a feature in your browser software.  If enabled, cookies store small amounts of data on your computer about actions you take on the pages of our Website.  Cookies assist us in tracking which of our features you visit most often, and what content you viewed on past visits.  When you visit this Website again, cookies allow us to remember you’re your settings and may be used for authentication.  We may use cookies to keep track of the number of return visits, accumulate and aggregate statistical information generally pertaining to our Website, and deliver specific content to you based on your past viewing history.  You can disable cookies, although our Website may not function properly for you.  Your browser preferences can be modified to accept or reject all cookies, or request a notification when a cookie is set. You may read more about cookies at http://cookiecentral.com.  In order to use all of the features and functionality of our Website, you need to accept cookie. We may also allow third party vendors and advertisers to set their own cookies on and through our Website.  We have no control over the practices of those third parties and are not responsible for their technology or tracking.  We encourage you to review the policies of such persons or entities on their websites.

2.4.  We as well as third party vendors and supporting advertisers may also use pixels to collect information about your visit to the Website, measure and improve the effectiveness of advertisements, and track delivery of advertising. Web Beacons collect only a limited set of information including a cookie number, time and date of page view, as well as a description of the page on which the Web Beacon resides.  We may also use Web beacons in the Newsletter.  This allows us to determine if you opened or acted upon the email messages.  Because Web beacons are the same as any other content request, you cannot opt out or refuse them.  However, they can be rendered ineffective by either opting out of cookies or changing the cookie setup in your browser. For more information about web beacons, visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org/faqs/beacons.html](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/faqs/beacons.html).

2.5.  We obtain Website and Newsletter usage information from Google Analytics, as described below.

2.6.  We obtain information about the effectiveness of advertising campaigns on the Newsletter and the Website.

##  **3\. How We Use Information**

3.1.      We use your e-mail address to deliver the Newsletter, unless you have opted out. We may share your personal information with our corporate affiliates and our cloud-based service providers. We may also share your personal information with law enforcement and/or government agencies (a) if required by law or to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process, or (b) when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.  Otherwise, except as expressly set forth in this policy, we do not share your e-mail address or other personal information with anyone.

3.2.  We use aggregated, anonymous non-personal information to operate and improve the website.

3.3.  We share aggregated, anonymous non-personal information with third parties, so that they can understand the kinds of visitors that come to the Website. For example, we might tell our advertisers the average income of our subscribers.

##  **4\. Third Party Information Collection**

 ** ** 4.1.  We utilize Google Analytics to collect Website and Newsletter usage information. Google collects usage information about the Website and Newsletter. Google Analytics utilizes the data collected through its cookies to track and examine the use of this Website, to prepare reports on its activities, and to share them with other Google services. You may opt-out of the Google Analytics service using Google’s Browser Add-available at [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

4.2.  We utilize Google AdSense to run advertising campaigns on the Website and the Newsletter. Google and other third parties collect information about your usage of the Website and about the effectiveness of these advertising campaigns. They use this information to display interest-based advertising, which they believe is relevant to you.

4.3.  Certain third parties provide functionality on our website, such as social media sharing and the commenting function. These third parties may collect non-personal information about you. Please see their privacy policies for more information.

##  **5\. Opt-Out**

5.1.  You can unsubscribe from receiving our e-mails at any time. You can unsubscribe by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link in the footer of our emails and following the instructions. You can also unsubscribe by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link on this site and following the instructions or by sending us a message to contact@idropnews.com.

5.2.  You can unsubscribe from receiving our browser notifications at any time. Visit our notifications page by clicking on the “Notifications” link on this site and follow the instructions.

5.3  As detailed above, we as well as third party vendors and supporting advertisers may use technology to collect various types of non-personal information in the form of cookies and pixels.  You have the right and ability to opt-out of our collection and use of this technology as set forth above in Section 2. The use of cookies and pixels by third party vendors and supporting advertisers is subject to their own respective privacy policies and not ours.

If you prefer to not receive targeted advertising from third party vendors and supporting advertisers, you can opt-out of some network advertising programs that use your information. To do so, please visit the [DAA Opt-Out Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). Please note that even if you choose to opt-out of targeted advertising, you will still see advertisements while you’re browsing online, including this Website. However, the advertisements you see may be less relevant to you and your interests. Additionally, many network advertising programs allow you to view and manage the interest categories they have compiled from your online browsing activities. These interest categories help determine the types of targeted advertisements you may receive. The DAA Opt-Out Page provides a tool that identifies its member companies that have cookies on your browser and provides links to those companies.

## 6\. Storage

6.1.  We store and retain your personal information for a long as you use the Site and/or remain subscribed to the Newsletter. Notwithstanding the foregoing, we may store and retain your personal information for a reasonable time of up to 90 days after you stop using the Website and/or unsubscribed to the Newsletter for internal reporting and analytics and improving the Website and/or any product or services provided thereto.  We may retain various types of information for longer periods pursuant to legal requirements under applicable law. We will make efforts to guarantee that personal information is kept for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the personal information is processed. The information that we store may be deleted as space requires or in the normal course of business. 

To opt-out of receiving more information about our products and services or our emails, you may send an email to [contact@idropnews.com](mailto:contact@idropnews.com).

## 7\. Information for EU Residents (General Data Protection Regulation)

If you are a EU resident, the following additional terms apply to your use of this Website from May 25, 2018 onward. 

7.1. For purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), we are a data controller, as such term is defined by the GDPR, and therefore we are responsible for, and control, the processing of your personal information in accordance with the requirements of GDPR. 

Under the GDPR, we may only process your personal information if we have a legal basis for doing so. For our Newsletter, our legal basis for processing is consent, which consent is obtained when you subscribe to our Newsletter and voluntarily provide your personal information to us.  For any other purposes, we otherwise rely on legitimate interest as the basis for processing your personal information. 

7.2   For information regarding the types of information we collect from EU residents, how we collect that information, and how we use that information, please review Sections 1, 2, and 3 of this policy. 

7.3   For information regarding our data retention practices, please review Section 6 of this policy.  You may unsubscribe from the Newsletter or request that we delete your personal information by following the instructions provided immediately below. 

7.4   If you are a EU resident, your personal information is processed and stored by Amazon Web Services (AWS) Cloud in the United States on our behalf in accordance with the highest degree of security of AWS.  To the extent necessary under EU privacy laws and regulations, we enter into model contractual clauses to ensure an adequate level of protection is provided for personal information transferred outside of the EU. 

  7. 5 If you have previously given consent by subscribing to our Newsletter, you may freely withdraw such consent at any time by either clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link in the footer of our emails and following the instructions, by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link on this Website and following the instructions, or by emailing us at [contact@idropnews.com](mailto:contact@idropnews.com). 

7.6  Beginning May 25, 2018, the GDPR provides you, as an EU resident, with certain legal rights with respect to the personal information that we hold and/or process regarding you.  These legal rights are set forth below. If you wish to exercise any of these legal rights, you should put your request in writing and email it to us at [contact@idropnews.com](mailto:contact@idropnews.com) with “GDPR Data Subject Rights Request” as the subject line.  Please provide enough information for us to identify you and to respond to your request. 

Your rights as an individual based in the EU:

  * Access to your information: You have the right to request a copy of the personal information we hold about you.
  * Correcting your information: You have the right to have any inaccurate information we hold about you to be corrected and/or updated. We want to have accurate data. Please contact us if you think the data we hold is not up to date or correct. 
  * Deletion of your information: You have the right to ask us to delete personal information about you if it no longer is required for the purpose it was collected, you have withdrawn your consent, you have a valid objection to us using your personal information, or our use of your personal information is contrary to law or our other legal obligations.
  * Objecting to how we may use your information: You have the right at any time to require us to stop using your personal information.  If so, we shall stop processing your personal information unless we can demonstrate sufficient and compelling legitimate grounds for continuing the processing which override your own interests. If, as a result of your circumstances, you do not have the right to object to such processing, then we will let you know. 
  * Restricting how we may use your information: You have the right in certain circumstances to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information, for example where the personal information Is inaccurate or where you have objected to the processing (see bullet point above). 

7.7  If you have any questions or complaints or wish to contact our Data Protection Officer, please email us at [contact@idropnews.com](mailto:contact@idropnews.com).   

## Miscellaneous

8.1. We do not knowingly collect any personal information about children under the age of 13. If we obtain actual knowledge that we have collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from our database.

8.2. We do not collect information about your past, present or potential future medical conditions or treatments.

8.3.  The Website does not honor the “do not track” signal sent by some web browsers.

8.4.  We may disclose your information if legally required to do so, or at our discretion, pursuant to a request from a governmental entity, or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect our rights or property, or our affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime; or (d) protect the personal safety of users or the public.

8.5.  We may disclose and transfer your information to a third party who acquires any or all of our business, whether such acquisition is by way of merger, consolidation or purchase of all or a substantial portion of our assets.  Such a third party will be bound by this privacy policy.

8.6  We may make changes to this policy in the future. If any important changes occur, we will notify you through one of our newsletters and notifications.

8.7.  If you have questions about this policy, or about the website in general, please write to us at contact@idropnews.com or visit here to find other ways to get in touch with us.

 **Contact Us**

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact:

iDrop News

3770 Hwy 165 Ste C-164

Pineville, LA 71360

Email: privacy@idropnews.com

Phone: +1-318-319-0133

* * *

## EU Cookie Policy
